

Av de Valdemarin 91A 1°D. 28023. Madrid. España

□ (+34) 651 808 171 | work@pabloforero.eu | www.pabloforero.eu | pforero | pforero

Introducción

Data Scientist at Allfunds' Innovation Lab. Strong analytical and technological skills. Specialist in modelling and predictive analysis. Stochastic models, time series, dynamic programming, machine learning and neural networks. Enthusiast of free open source software and modern industry practices.

Experiencia Profesional

Allfunds Madrid, Spain

DATA SCIENTIST, INNOVATION LAB

2018 - Present

- · Developed a predictive model using Random Forests, in order to profile retail costumers fund buying preferences.
- · Started an experimental project for classifying share classes using Natural Langugage Processing with prospectus in PDF format.
- Defined and analysed a project to implement a company wide CRM.
- Assisted in the development of a company Datalake
- Minerva
- · Daily email.
- · Eva.
- Arcus

SAIS John Hopkins University

Bologna, Italy

TEACHING ASSISTANT 201

• Teaching assistant in International Trade for Professor G. Plummer.

Banif (Santander Private Banking)

Madrid, Spain

ANALYST, ASSET MANAGEMENT

2009 - 2010

- · Support/Analysis.
- · Fixed Income.

Renaissance Capital

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

• Sub-saharan Emerging Markets.

CQS Hedge Fund

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

2007

· Pension Plans.

ING Capital
Intern, Research

London, UK

· Easter European Emerging Markets.

Educación

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

Ph.D. (ABD) IN ECONOMICS

2012 - 2017

- Thesis title: Competition, Tasks and Earnings Inequality
- Supervisor: Ramon Marimón

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

MRES IN ECONOMICS

2013

Universidad de Navarra

MSc in Economics and Finance

amplona, Spair

University of Exeter

Exeter, UK

2011

B.A. IN ECONOMICS AND POLITICS

2006 - 2009

Actividades Profesionales

EABCN Training School Florence, Italy

2016

2016

PARTICIPANT

• Micro-Structure of Trade - Theory and Evidence

• Taught by Klaus Adam

Workshop on Economic Policy Challenges Florence, Italy

DISCUSSANT

• The Optimal Inflation Rate and Firm-Level Productivity Trends

• By Klaus Adam and Henning Weber

The Econometric Society 2016 European Winter Meeting Edinburgh, UK

Presenting 2016

Simposio de la Asociación Española de Economía

Bilbao, Spain

Presenting 2016

Zurich Initiative on Computational EconomicsZurich, Switzerland

PARTICIPANT 2015

COEURE Workshop on Labour Markets

Brussels, Belgium

RAPPORTFUR 2015

• EU Dual Labour Markets: Consequences and Potential Reforms

Conocimientos

Research International Trade, Macroeconomics, Labour Economics, Computational Economics

Languages Spanish, English, French (Basic), Italian (Basic)

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, SQL, LaTeX, Julia, VBA

Statistical Tools Excel, Dynare, Eviews, Stata

Cloud Tools BigQuery, Google Storage, Composer **Tools** Docker, Sphinx, Git, Office, Airflow, PyTorch